Harvard College Observatory observations, logs, instrument readings, and calculations: an inventory
Harvard College Observatory observations, logs, instrument readings, and calculations
1750-1990
Harvard College Observatory.
KG11365-6
120 cubic feet 120 boxes
2531 volumes
- Transit Circle, 1848-11-07/1849-07-30; phaedra0001 (Box 1)
  KG Number:
  KG11365.1
  Sequence volume:
  A1
  Authors:
  George Phillips Bond, Richard F. Bond
  ADS Record:
  1848phae.proj....1B
  Scope and Contents
  Annotated May 1854
- Transit Circle, 1849-07-30/1849-09-25; phaedra0002 (Box 1)
  KG11365.2
  A2
  George Phillips Bond, William Cranch Bond
  1849phae.proj....2B
- Transit Circle, 1849-09-26/1849-11-29; phaedra0003 (Box 1)
  KG11365.3
  A3
  William Cranch Bond, Richard F. Bond
  1849phae.proj....3B
- Transit Circle, 1849-11-30/1850-02-06; phaedra0004 (Box 1)
  KG11365.4
  A4
  George Phillips Bond, Benjamin Peirce
  1849phae.proj....4B
- Transit Circle, 1850-02-06/1850-04-30; phaedra0005 (Box 1)
  KG11365.5
  A5
  George Phillips Bond, William Cranch Bond, Richard F. Bond
  1850phae.proj....5B
- Transit Circle, 1850-05-01/1850-10-20; phaedra0006 (Box 1)
  KG11365.6
  A6
  George Phillips Bond, William Cranch Bond, Charles W. Tuttle
  1850phae.proj....6B
  Contains a note of introduction for Charles W. Tuttle (1850-07-12)
- Transit Circle, 1850-10-21/1850-12-26; phaedra0007 (Box 1)
  KG11365.7
  A7
  1850phae.proj....7B
- Transit Circle [Electric Telegraph], 1850-12-26/1851-04-03; phaedra0008 (Box 1)
  KG11365.8
  A8
  Charles W. Tuttle, George Phillips Bond
  1850phae.proj....8T
- Transit Circle, 1851-04-03/1851-07-13; phaedra0009 (Box 1)
  KG11365.9
  A9
  Author:
  Charles W. Tuttle
  1851phae.proj....9T
- Transit Circle [Solar Eclipse 7/28], 1851-07-13/1851-09-05; phaedra0010 (Box 1)
  KG11365.10
  A10
  Charles W. Tuttle, William Cranch Bond
  1851phae.proj...10T
  Contains a note describing the daguerreotype photography during the 1851 July eclipse, those present, their tasks, and the timing of each daguerreotype
- Transit Circle [Asteroids], 1851-09-05/1852-01-15; phaedra0011 (Box 1)
  KG11365.11
  A11
  1851phae.proj...11T
- Transit Circle, 1852-01-15/1852-06-28; phaedra0012 (Box 1)
  KG11365.12
  A12
  1852phae.proj...12T
- Transit Circle, 1852-06-28/1852-12-05; phaedra0013 (Box 1)
  KG11365.13
  A13
  1852phae.proj...13T
- Transit Circle, 1852-12-01/1853-07-08; phaedra0014 (Box 1)
  KG11365.14
  A14
  1852phae.proj...14T
  Describes an experiment to ascertain the speed of sound
- Transit Circle, 1853-07-08/1854-02-26; phaedra0015 (Box 1)
  KG11365.15
  A15
  George Phillips Bond, Charles W. Tuttle
  1853phae.proj...15B
- Transit Circle, 1854-02-28/1854-08-15; phaedra0016 (Box 1)
  KG11365.16
  A16
  William Cranch Bond, George Phillips Bond, Charles W. Tuttle
  1854phae.proj...16B
- Transit Circle, 1854-08-15/1854-11-27; phaedra0017 (Box 1)
  KG11365.17
  A17
  1854phae.proj...17B
- Transit Circle, 1854-11-27/1855-01-25; phaedra0018 (Box 1)
  KG11365.18
  A18
  William Cranch Bond, Truman Henry Safford, Philip Sidney Coolidge, Charles W. Tuttle
  1854phae.proj...18B
- Transit Circle, 1855-01-25/1855-05-06; phaedra0019 (Box 1)
  KG11365.19
  A19
  William Cranch Bond, Truman Henry Safford, Philip Sidney Coolidge
  1855phae.proj...19B
- Transit Circle, 1855-05-06/1855-07-31; phaedra0020 (Box 1)
  KG11365.20
  A20
  William Cranch Bond, Philip Sidney Coolidge
  1855phae.proj...20B
- Harvard Transit Circle, 1855-08-01/1855-09-25; phaedra0021 (Box 1)
  KG11365.21
  A21
  William Cranch Bond, Philip Sidney Coolidge, Charles W. Tuttle, J.F. Flagg
  1855phae.proj...21B
- Transit Circle [Eclipse], 1855-09-25/1856-03-27; phaedra0022 (Box 1)
  KG11365.22
  A22
  William Cranch Bond, Philip Sidney Coolidge, Truman Henry Safford, J.F. Flagg
  1855phae.proj...22B
- Transit Circle, 1856-03-27/1856-06-15; phaedra0023 (Box 1)
  KG11365.23
  A23
  1856phae.proj...23B
- Transits, 1856-06-16/1856-09-05; phaedra0024 (Box 1)
  KG11365.24
  A24
  1856phae.proj...24B
- Transits, Names of the asteroids, and observations of Polaris, 1856-09-08/1857-02-09; phaedra0025 (Box 1)
  KG11365.25
  A25
  William Cranch Bond, Philip Sidney Coolidge, Truman Henry Safford, Richard F. Bond, Horace P. Tuttle
  1856phae.proj...25B
- Transit Circle, New Group of Five wires, 1857-02-17/1857-09-21; phaedra0026 (Box 1)
  KG11365.26
  A26
  William Cranch Bond, Philip Sidney Coolidge, Truman Henry Safford, Richard F. Bond, Horace P. Tuttle, Asaph Hall
  1857phae.proj...26B
- Transit Circle, 1857-09-21/1857-11-03; phaedra0027 (Box 1)
  KG11365.27
  A27
  George Phillips Bond, Philip Sidney Coolidge, Asaph Hall
  1857phae.proj...27B
- Transit Circle, 1857-11-03/1858-02-10; phaedra0028 (Box 1)
  KG11365.28
  A28
  Asaph Hall, Philip Sidney Coolidge, Horace P. Tuttle
  1857phae.proj...28H
- Transit Circle, 1858-02-10/1858-07-05; phaedra0029 (Box 1)
  KG11365.29
  A29
  Asaph Hall, George Phillips Bond, Horace P. Tuttle, William Cranch Bond
  1858phae.proj...29H
- Transit Circle, 1858-07-05/1859-01-24; phaedra0030 (Box 1)
  KG11365.30
  A30
  Asaph Hall, William Cranch Bond
  1858phae.proj...30H
- Transit Circle, 1859-01-24/1859-08-17; phaedra0031 (Box 1)
  KG11365.31
  A31
  Asaph Hall, George Phillips Bond, Horace P. Tuttle
  1859phae.proj...31H
- Transit Circle, 1859-08-17/1860-01-23; phaedra0032 (Box 1)
  KG11365.32
  A32
  1859phae.proj...32H
- Transit Insturment, 1860-01-23/1860-06-23; phaedra0033 (Box 1)
  KG11365.33
  A33
  1860phae.proj...33H
- Transit Insturment, 1860-06-23/1860-11-29; phaedra0034 (Box 1)
  KG11365.34
  A34
  1860phae.proj...34H
- Transit Circle, 1860-11-29/1861-03-21; phaedra0035 (Box 1)
  KG11365.35
  A35
  1860phae.proj...35H
- Transit Circle, 1861-03-21/1861-10-01; phaedra0036 (Box 1)
  KG11365.36
  A36
  Asaph Hall, Truman Henry Safford, Horace P. Tuttle
  1861phae.proj...36H
- Transit Circle, 1861-10-01/1862-03-28; phaedra0037 (Box 1)
  KG11365.37
  A37
  1861phae.proj...37H
- Meridian Circle, 1862-03-28/1862-05-07; phaedra0038 (Box 1)
  KG11365.38
  A38
  Asaph Hall, Truman Henry Safford
  1862phae.proj...38H
- Meridian Circle, 1862-05-07/1862-08-06; phaedra0039 (Box 1)
  KG11365.39
  A39
  1862phae.proj...39H
- Meridian Circle, 1862-08-11/1862-09-25; phaedra0040 (Box 1)
  KG11365.40
  A40
  Truman Henry Safford
  1862phae.proj...40S
- Meridian Circle, 1862-09-27/1862-12-08; phaedra0041 (Box 1)
  KG11365.41
  A41
  1862phae.proj...41S
- Meridian Circle, 1862-12-10/1863-02-16; phaedra0042 (Box 1)
  KG11365.42
  A42
  1862phae.proj...42S
- Meridian Circle, 1863-02-17/1863-05-25; phaedra0043 (Box 1)
  KG11365.43
  A43
  1863phae.proj...43S
- Meridian Circle, 1863-05-26/1863-08-14; phaedra0044 (Box 1)
  KG11365.44
  A44
  1863phae.proj...44S
- Meridian Circle, 1863-08-14/1863-09-22; phaedra0045 (Box 2)
  KG11365.45
  A45
- Meridian Circle, 1863-09-23/1863-12-02; phaedra0046 (Box 2)
  KG11365.46
  A46
- Meridian Circle, 1863-12-05/1864-01-11; phaedra0047 (Box 2)
  KG11365.47
  A47
- Meridian Circle, 1864-01-11/1864-03-03; phaedra0048 (Box 2)
  KG11365.48
  A48
- Meridian Circle, 1864-03-07/1864-04-09; phaedra0049 (Box 2)
  KG11365.49
  A49
- Meridian Circle, 1864-04-09/1864-05-19; phaedra0050 (Box 2)
  KG11365.50
  A50
- Meridian Circle, 1864-05-22/1864-06-06; phaedra0051 (Box 2)
  KG11365.51
  A51
- Meridian Circle, 1864-06-07/1864-06-19; phaedra0052 (Box 2)
  KG11365.52
  A52
- Meridian Circle, 1864-06-21/1864-07-05; phaedra0053 (Box 2)
  KG11365.53
  A53
- Meridian Circle, 1864-07-06/1864-07-19; phaedra0054 (Box 2)
  KG11365.54
  A54
- Meridian Circle, 1864-07-20/1864-09-09; phaedra0055 (Box 2)
  KG11365.55
  A55
- Meridian Circle, 1864-09-10/1864-10-10; phaedra0056 (Box 2)
  KG11365.56
  A56
- Meridian Circle, 1864-10-10/1864-11-04; phaedra0057 (Box 2)
  KG11365.57
  A57
- Meridian Circle, 1864-11-10/1864-11-23; phaedra0058 (Box 2)
  KG11365.58
  A58
- Meridian Circle, 1864-11-25/1864-12-20; phaedra0059 (Box 2)
  KG11365.59
  A59
- Meridian Circle, 1864-12-30/1865-01-18; phaedra0060 (Box 2)
  KG11365.60
  A60
- Meridian Circle, 1865-01-20/1865-02-01; phaedra0061 (Box 2)
  KG11365.61
  A61
- Meridian Circle, 1865-02-02/1865-02-25; phaedra0062 (Box 2)
  KG11365.62
  A62
- Meridian Circle, 1865-02-27/1865-04-03; phaedra0063 (Box 2)
  KG11365.63
  A63
- Meridian Circle, 1865-04-03/1865-04-26; phaedra0064 (Box 2)
  KG11365.64
  A64
- Meridian Circle, 1865-05-01/1865-06-02; phaedra0065 (Box 2)
  KG11365.65
  A65
- Meridian Circle, 1865-06-03/1865-07-04; phaedra0066 (Box 2)
  KG11365.66
  A66
- Meridian Circle, 1865-07-18/1868-07-05; phaedra0067 (Box 2)
  KG11365.67
  A67
- Meridian Circle, 1865-07-20/1865-08-01; phaedra0068 (Box 2)
  KG11365.68
  A68
- Meridian Circle, 1865-08-02/1865-08-28; phaedra0069 (Box 2)
  KG11365.69
  A69
- Meridian Circle, 1865-08-29/1865-09-15; phaedra0070 (Box 2)
  KG11365.70
  A70
- Meridian Circle, 1865-09-16/1865-09-30; phaedra0071 (Box 2)
  KG11365.71
  A71
- Reduction of Transits, 1849-01-01/1849-08-16; phaedra0072 (Box 2)
  KG11365.72
  B1
- Reduction of Transits, 1849-08-16/1849-12-07; phaedra0073 (Box 2)
  KG11365.73
  B2
- Reduction of Transits, 1849-12-07/1850-04-02; phaedra0074 (Box 2)
  KG11365.74
  B3
- Reduction of Transits, 1850-04-02/1850-10-05; phaedra0075 (Box 2)
  KG11365.75
  B4
- Reduction of Transits, 1850-10-05/1850-12-30; phaedra0076 (Box 2)
  KG11365.76
  B5
- Reduction of Transits, 1850-12-30/1851-04-05; phaedra0077 (Box 2)
  KG11365.77
  B6
- Reduction of Transits, 1851-04-05/1851-07-08; phaedra0078 (Box 2)
  KG11365.78
  B7
- Reduction of Transits, 1851-07-08/1851-09-04; phaedra0079 (Box 2)
  KG11365.79
  B8
- Reduction of Transits, 1851-09-04/1851-11-11; phaedra0080 (Box 2)
  KG11365.80
  B9
- Reduction of Transits, 1851-11-11/1852-02-25; phaedra0081 (Box 2)
  KG11365.81
  B10
- Reduction of Transits, 1852-02-25/1852-07-06; phaedra0082 (Box 2)
  KG11365.82
  B11
- Reduction of Transits, 1852-07-06/1852-11-17; phaedra0083 (Box 2)
  KG11365.83
  B12
- Reduction of Transits, 1852-11-17/1853-05-01; phaedra0084 (Box 2)
  KG11365.84
  B13
- Reduction of Transits, 1853-05-01/1853-11-02; phaedra0085 (Box 2)
  KG11365.85
  B14
- Reduction of Transits, 1853-11-02/1854-04-04; phaedra0086 (Box 2)
  KG11365.86
  B15
- Reduction of Transits, 1854-04-04/1854-08-09; phaedra0087 (Box 2)
  KG11365.87
  B16
- Reduction of Transits, 1854-08-06/1854-11-27; phaedra0088 (Box 2)
  KG11365.88
  B17
- Reduction of Transits, 1854-11-27/1855-01-30; phaedra0089 (Box 2)
  KG11365.89
  B18
- Reduction of Transits, 1855-01-30/1855-05-06; phaedra0090 (Box 2)
  KG11365.90
  B19
- Reduction of Transits, 1855-05-06/1855-08-01; phaedra0091 (Box 2)
  KG11365.91
  B20
- Reduction of Transits, 1855-07-31/1855-09-25; phaedra0092 (Box 3)
  KG11365.92
  B21
- Reduction of Transits, 1855-09-25/1856-03-30; phaedra0093 (Box 3)
  KG11365.93
  B22
- Reduction of Transits, 1856-03-30/1856-06-11; phaedra0094 (Box 3)
  KG11365.94
  B23
- Reduction of Transits, 1856-06-11/1856-08-22; phaedra0095 (Box 3)
  KG11365.95
  B24
- Reduction of Transits, 1856-08-22/1856-11-20; phaedra0096 (Box 3)
  KG11365.96
  B25
- Reduction of Transits, 1856-11-20/1857-04-30; phaedra0097 (Box 3)
  KG11365.97
  B26
- Reduction of Transits, 1857-04-30/1857-10-04; phaedra0098 (Box 3)
  KG11365.98
  B27
- Reduction of Transits, 1857-10-04/1857-11-28; phaedra0099 (Box 3)
  KG11365.99
  B28
- Reduction of Transits, 1857-11-28/1858-02-23; phaedra0100 (Box 3)
  KG11365.100
  B29
- Reduction of Transits, 1858-02-23/1858-06-24; phaedra0101 (Box 3)
  KG11365.101
  B30
- Reduction of Transits, 1858-06-24/1858-11-09; phaedra0102 (Box 3)
  KG11365.102
  B31
- Reduction of Transits, 1858-11-09/1859-06-19; phaedra0103 (Box 3)
  KG11365.103
  B32
- Reduction of Transits, 1859-06-19/1859-10-14; phaedra0104 (Box 3)
  KG11365.104
  B33
- Reduction of Transits, 1859-10-14/1860-03-27; phaedra0105 (Box 3)
  KG11365.105
  B34
- Reduction of Transits, 1860-03-27/1860-11-16; phaedra0106 (Box 3)
  KG11365.106
  B35
- Reduction of Transits, 1860-11-16/1861-01-01; phaedra0107 (Box 3)
  KG11365.107
  B36
- North and South Meridian Marks and Level Readings, 1849-12-05/1853-07-04; phaedra0108 (Box 3)
  KG11365.108
  C1
- North and South Meridian Marks and Level Readings, 1853-07-01/1855-04-21; phaedra0109 (Box 3)
  KG11365.109
  C2
- North and South Meridian Marks and Level Readings, 1855-04-21/1856-09-08; phaedra0110 (Box 3)
  KG11365.110
  C3
- North and South Meridian Marks and Level Readings, 1856-09-01/1859-02-24; phaedra0111 (Box 3)
  KG11365.111
  C4
- North and South Meridian Marks and Level Readings, 1859-02-24/1862-03-11; phaedra0112 (Box 3)
  KG11365.112
  C5
- Instrumental Corrections, 1863-12-29/1865-10-01; phaedra0113 (Box 3)
  KG11365.113
  C8
- Computed AR of Polar Stars, 1862-03-11/1863-08-19; phaedra0114 (Box 3)
  KG11365.114
  C9
- Computed AR of Polar Stars, 1863-08-22/1864-11-14; phaedra0115 (Box 3)
  KG11365.115
  C10
- Chronograph Record, 1861-06-01/1863-07-01; phaedra0116 (Box 3)
  KG11365.116
  C11
- Chronograph Record, 1863-07-23/1864-11-04; phaedra0117 (Box 3)
  KG11365.117
  C12
- Chronograph Record, 1864-11-10/1865-09-12; phaedra0118 (Box 3)
  KG11365.118
  C13
- Chronograph Record, 1865-09-13/1866-02-20; phaedra0119 (Box 3)
  KG11365.119
  C14
- Miscellaneous time observations, phaedra0120 (Box 3)
  KG11365.120
  C12[C15]
- Minutes of Chronometer Expect., 1849-04-01/1850-02-01; phaedra0121 (Box 3)
  KG11365.121
  D1
  Includes correspondence with Professor J. Wenlock (Identity uncertain)
- Meridian Circle, 1859-11-07/1860-05-25; phaedra0122 (Box 3)
  KG11365.122
  E1
- Meridian Circle, 1859-05-24/1859-11-03; phaedra0123 (Box 3)
  KG11365.123
  E2
- Meridian Circle, 1860-05-25/1860-11-13; phaedra0124 (Box 3)
  KG11365.124
  E3
- Declinations, 1862-12-20/1863-09-09; phaedra0125 (Box 3)
  KG11365.125
  E4
- Declinations, 1863-09-14/1864-10-17; phaedra0126 (Box 3)
  KG11365.126
  E5
- New Observations, Transit Circle [Venus], 1857-02-17/1858-05-28; phaedra0127 (Box 3)
  KG11365.127
  E6
- Transit Circle, 1851/1853; phaedra0128 (Box 3)
  KG11365.128
  E7
- Transit Circle, 1851-08-07/1851-12-04; phaedra0129 (Box 3)
  KG11365.129
  E8
- Moon Culminations and Transits, Comets, 1845-12-01/1846-04-01; phaedra0130 (Box 3)
  KG11365.130
  F1
- Comets and Meridian Transits [Earthquake 8/25/1846], 1846-04-01/1846-10-01; phaedra0131 (Box 3)
  KG11365.131
  F2
- Comets and Meridian Transits, 1846-10-01/1847-04-16; phaedra0132 (Box 3)
  KG11365.132
  F3
- Comets and Meridian Transits, 1847-04-24/1848-02-09; phaedra0133 (Box 3)
  KG11365.133
  F4
- Comets and Meridian Transits, 1848-02-18/1848-08-01; phaedra0134 (Box 3)
  KG11365.134
  F5
- Comets and Meridian Transits, 1849-08-01/1850-02-27; phaedra0135 (Box 3)
  KG11365.135
  F6
- Meridian and Prime Vertical Observations, 1844-11-06/1844-12-12; phaedra0136 (Box 3)
  KG11365.136
  F7
- West Transit, 1851-11-05/1851-12-16; phaedra0137 (Box 3)
  KG11365.137
  F8
- Prime Vertical, 1854-11-18; phaedra0138 (Box 3)
  KG11365.138
  F9
- Magnetic and Prime Vertical, 1858; phaedra0139 (Box 3)
  KG11365.139
  F10
- Terrestrial Magnetism, 1858-03-25/1861-06-05; phaedra0140 (Box 3)
  KG11365.140
  F11
- Chronograph, 1864-06-08/1864-07-21; phaedra0141 (Box 4)
  KG11365.141
  F12a
  Physical condition:
  Mold damaged
- Prime vertical computation of Latitude, 1864; phaedra0142 (Box 4)
  KG11365.142
  F12b
- Telegraph, 1848-07-06/1848-10-28; phaedra0143 (Box 4)
  KG11365.143
  F13
  William Cranch Bond, George Phillips Bond, Richard F. Bond, Elias Loomis
  Programme of Telegraph operations from Cambridge observatory (C) to Newyork [sic] Observatory (N) for 1848
  Observations for clock corrections for Telegraph Operations; Transits July 8th 1848; Aurora; E Bootis, a2 Libra, B Librae, a Corona Borealis, a Serpentis; Polaris; Spica; Lyra; Star Signals; Immersion of Librae; Observations for Personal equation between WCB and Prof. Loomis; Arcturus illumination day light.
- Chronometers, 1851-10-06/1853-07-01; phaedra0144 (Box 4)
  KG11365.144
  G1
  Telegraph Signals; Sidereal Chronometer Records; R.F. Bond to Halifax; Chronometer sent to Charleston, South Carolina; Mean Time Clock; Time for Boston; Transit of Arcturus
- Chronometers (Annular Eclipse 5/26/1854), 1853-07-01/1855-04-21; phaedra0145 (Box 4)
  KG11365.145
  G2
  Daily time records; Annular Eclipse of May 26; Remarks by W.C.B.; Meteorological Remarks
- Sidereal and Mean Time Clocks, 1856-01-01/1856-04-21; phaedra0146 (Box 4)
  KG11365.146
  G3
  William Cranch Bond, George Phillips Bond, Philip Sidney Coolidge, Richard F. Bond, Charles W. Tuttle, J.F. Flagg
  Comparisons by 12MT- Comparators -1107 and 1508; Comparison of chronometers with MTC - by aid of 6hr; Comparisons with comparator No. 1508; 1855 June 5th Last comparison before embarcation; Direct comparisons; Comparison of chronometer Thomas Adams No 3585;Comparator Y (No. 1107 -)(copied from the paper found in the top); Sidereal Chronometer No. 3585; Errors of Chronometers on Greenwich M.S.T.; Notes documenting return of specific chronometers following examination; Direct comparison of chronometers on Tuesday before they were put on board the Africa; Coast Survey Chronometric Expedition
- Sidereal and Mean Time Clocks, 1856-01-01/1857-02-27; phaedra0147 (Box 4)
  KG11365.147
  G4
  George Phillips Bond, Asaph Hall
  Timings of chronometers and Mean Time clocks; notes on clock adjustments; Note of offer by Mr. Dodge to sell telegraph lines to the observatory
- Sidereal and Mean Time Clocks, 1856-07-02/1857-02-27; phaedra0148 (Box 4)
  KG11365.148
  G5
  George Phillips Bond, William Cranch Bond, Richard F. Bond, Philip Sidney Coolidge, Asaph Hall
  Questions propounded by Mr Briggs, relative to his clock with a circulating pendulum; Comparison of sidereal clock with that containing Briggs patent circulating pendulum; recorded chronometer timings; Lieut. Ives set up his transit instrument on the stand of our variation-transit and obtained the following y E.C. and the Spring-governor.; Result, time to be given 4 1/2 seconds sooner at Cambridge than the bells at Boston should strike.
- Sidereal and Mean Time Clocks, 1858-07-02/1860-07-16; phaedra0149 (Box 4)
  KG11365.149
  G6
  Data relating to timing output of various clocks and chronometers.
- Sidereal and Mean Time Clocks, 1860-07-16/1862-09-03; phaedra0150 (Box 4)
  KG11365.150
  G7
  1860 July 17/18: "These chronometers were used for observing the solar eclipse. See Transit Book of this date."; "Corrections of the New Clock. (Isody. Escap.) [i.e., Isodynamic Escapement] Oct. 23 1860 to Apr. 8 1861; Timing data recorded for various devices; Cambridge and Boston
- Sidereal and Mean Time Clocks, 1862-09-16/1866-03-02; phaedra0151 (Box 4)
  KG11365.151
  G8
  Small volume in back of box and out of numerical order
  Directions for Absolute Time; Brief Ephemeris for locally-viewed stars for May 1865; Eclipse of Sun - End West Wing Equatorial; Timing output data and status information relating to a number of chronometric devices
- Raliroad Time Commenced, 1854-06-29/1854-10-01; phaedra0152 (Box 4)
  KG11365.152
  Ga
  1854 June R.R. Regulators; Notes and recorded data relating to railroad watches
- Trials of Pendulums and Chronometers, 1857-04-27/1859-02-19; phaedra0153 (Box 4)
  KG11365.153
  Gb
  Recorded timing data relating to various clocks.
- [Comets and Double Stars], Volume 1, 1848-11-01/1849-02-01; phaedra0154 (Box 4)
  KG11365.154
  Ha
  George Phillips Bond, William Cranch Bond, Truman Henry Safford
  1848 June Measures of the Observatory Buildings Piers and Instruments.
  Ring of Saturn and other observations relating to planet including satellites; Enckes Comet; Observations of Jupiter; New comet first seen [Saturday, Nov. 25th]; Mercury; New satellite of Saturn [Dec. 18th]; Petersen's Comet; Nebula R 0h39m Dec -26 ..13'; Examination of Collimation of G[reat] R[efractor][Dec 28th]; Orion; satellite of Neptune; Notes on viewing conditions; Errors of the Equatorial [p. 605]
- Equatorial Reductions, 1860-06-21/1861-01-22; phaedra0155 (Box 4)
  KG11365.155
  Comet 1860 III: Mean Places for 1860.0 of Comparison Stars; Parallax; Coefficients and Parallax; Observations of Comet 1860 III made at the Observatory of Harvard College; Various Observations in 1859-60
- Equatorial, Volume 1, 1846-10-01/1847-07-01; phaedra0156 (Box 4)
  KG11365.156
  H1
  Observations on the New Planet; Observations of Meteors over several nights; Jupiter; Possible double star; Corrections for Refraction; Observations on Neptune Oct 1846 to Jun 1847; Andromeda; Saturn; Notice f Comet sent to [list inludes J.Q. Adams, Washington D.C.; First Observations with the Great Refractor [p. 65]; Great Equatorial Observations June 30th 1847; Elements of the Comet of March 4th 1847 From Observations on March 5th, 12th, 19th
- Equatorial, Volume 1, 1847-07-01/1847-12-01; phaedra0157 (Box 4)
  KG11365.157
  H2
  Opposition of Neptune; Observations on the Comet, July 1847; Observation of the Moon; First Occultation observed with the Great Refractor;; Note on observing the "division of Saturn's ring" [Aug 27th 1847]; Great Nebula in Andromeda; Jupiter; Immersion of 29 Ophiuci; Observations of Lasell's Satellite of Neptune; Mars; Observations of Venus; Observations for Personal Equations with Prof. S.C. Walker
  "Rev J H Clinch with us -"
  Maria Mitchell's Comet
  Illustrations: Mars; Andromeda star field including three nebulae; Venus; Neptune
- Equatorial, Volume 1, 1847-12-01/1848-08-01; phaedra0158 (Box 4)
  KG11365.158
  H3
  George Phillips Bond, William Cranch Bond, Charles S. Peirce
  Dimensions of Pier; Nebula in Andromeda; Nebula in Orion; Colla's Comet; Observations of Jupiter; New Nebula; Mauvais Comet; Polaris; Hind's New Star (Nova Ophiuci No. 2); xi Ursa Majoris; epsilon Bootis; Neptune; Saturn; Opposition of Neptune with a star of the 8th magnitude; Ephemeris of Encke's Comet for 1848 Computed by Prof. Peirce; Ephemeris of Colla's Comet (from C. con Litrow; Miss Mitchell's Comet; Ephemeris of Great Elongation of Satellites of Uranus
  Nebula in Andromeda; Nebula in Orion; Jupiter; a number of hand-drawn sky maps
- Equatorial, Volume 1, 1847-11-01/1848-02-01; phaedra0159 (Box 4)
  KG11365.159
  H4
  Contributor: Richard F. Bond
  Contributor:
  Richard F. Bond
  William Cranch Bond, George Phillips Bond
  Powers of the different eyepieces of the Great Telescope
  Orion Nebula; Mars; Jupiter; Lyra; Uranus and satellite; Trapezium; Andromeda; Occultation of 80 Piscium; 29 Ophiuci
  Drawings / Star Maps: pp. 260, 266, 267, 268, 270, 271, 272, 274, 283, 288, 292, 294, 295, 310, 319, 326, 327, 328, 331, 332
- Equatorial, Volume 1, 1848-02-01/1848-09-01; phaedra0160 (Box 4)
  KG11365.160
  H5
- Equatorial, Volume 1, 1848-05-01/1848-11-01; phaedra0161 (Box 4)
  KG11365.161
  H6
- Equatorial, Volume 2, 1849-02-01/1849-06-01; phaedra0162 (Box 4)
  KG11365.162
  H7
- Equatorial, Volume 2, 1849-01-01/1849-11-01; phaedra0163 (Box 4)
  KG11365.163
  H8
- Equatorial, Volume 2 [Daguerreotyping], 1849-12-01/1850-04-01; phaedra0164 (Box 4)
  KG11365.164
  H10
- Equatorial, Volume 2, 1850-05-10/1850-09-01; phaedra0165 (Box 4)
  KG11365.165
  H11
- Equatorial, Volume 2, 1850-09-21/1851-02-25; phaedra0166 (Box 4)
  KG11365.166
  H12
- Equatorial, Volume 2, 1851-02-25/1851-12-04; phaedra0167 (Box 4)
  KG11365.167
  H13
- Equatorial, Volume 3, 1851-12-04/1852-05-18; phaedra0168 (Box 4)
  KG11365.168
  H14
  Encke's Comet; Saturn and satellites; Orion; Mars; Contains sketches of Saturn and satellites; Aurora; Nebulae; Victoria; Trial of Clark 7.5 inch achromatic telescope; Spiral nebula in Canes Venatici
- Equatorial, Volume 3, 1852-05-19/1852-10-26; phaedra0169 (Box 4)
  KG11365.169
  H15
- Equatorial, Volume 3, 1852-10-28/1853-03-10; phaedra0170 (Box 4)
  KG11365.170
  H16
- Equatorial, Volume 3, 1853-03-10/1854-04-04; phaedra0171 (Box 4)
  KG11365.171
  H17
- Equatorial, Volume 3, 1854-04-04/1855-06-13; phaedra0172 (Box 4)
  KG11365.172
  H18